Jay Patel

Montreal, Quebec, Canada
M: +1 (514) 585-2098
E: pateljay2098@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jaypatel-35b969178

Website:

jyp2098.github.io/portfolio

Professional Summary

One and a half years of professional software development experience in Object Oriented Programming and web development. Selfmotivated, willing to learn new technologies to broaden my horizons and enhance knowledge in the everexpanding field of computer science.

Skills

- Programming Languages:
 Java, HTML, CSS,
 JavaScript, Python
- Frameworks:
 Node, React, React Native
- Tools:

Git, Visual Studio Code, Expo, Eclipse, Tableau, Anaconda, Unity

• Concepts:

REST APIs, MVC, Data Structures, Web/App Development, Machine Learning, Augmented Reality

 Soft skills: Written and verbal Communication, Management skills, Time Management Skills, Self-Motivated

Work Experience

Concordia University - Academic Information Technology Services (Service Desk Operator)
(Currently working)

- Provide academic computing, information services and applications to support teaching, administrative and research activities of students, staff and faculty of Gina Cody School of Engineering and ComputerScience.
- Querying Linux servers, SSH tunneling, and using the FootPrints ticketing portal to work with user queries.

Concordia University (*Teaching Assistant for COMP 353 - Databases*) (January 2022 – April 2022)

 Conduct tutorial sessions on SQL, properties and fundamentals of relational database

The Sparks Foundation (Data Science and Business Analytics Intern) (December 2020 - January 2021)

- Collect, crunch and analyze data from various sources
- Worked on Machine Learning tasks and tuning models

Goods India Carrier (Web developer) (September 2019 - April 2020)

- Worked on the company's website built on React JS
- Implemented REST APIs
- Experience of turning the software requirements into product features

Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Institute of Technology (Building the official college website)

(February 2019 - April 2019)

- Implemented RESTful Web Services with the framework Gatsby JS
- Practiced Agile methodology

WebMobi Technologies (Software Development Intern) (July 2018 - April 2019)

• Successfully learned and implemented different software development processes on Visual Studio.

Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Institute of Technology (Head of Registration Desk) (January 2017 - March 2017)

- Managed a team of 20 people for maintaining the database of students coming to the college for the national tech fest.
- Worked on MS Access and established LAN networks.

Education

Concordia University,

Montreal, Quebec, Canada Master of Applied Computer Science (Current CGPA 3.78/4.3)

Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Institute of Technology, Anand, Gujarat, India Bachelor of Engineering – Computer Engineering (CGPA 8.83/10

Projects

Voice Controlled News App

A React based news application built with Alan AI API to retrieve news articles from various news channels.

Google Clone

Clone of Google Search Engine using Google Custom Search API.

Gym Website

A gym website UI made with React and Framer Motion.

Self-driving Car with Behavioral Cloning

A machine learning project by which human sub cognitive skills can be captured and reproduced in a computer program and used in real world for developing autonomous vehicles.

Waves Music

A web-based music player app made with React JS

<u>P</u> <u>r</u> <u>o</u> <u>i</u>

e c t s : v

o i c e

C

o n t r o I

I

e d N e w

A p

p